<resources>

    <string name="app_name">Perfect Pi</string>
    <string name="about_app_name">About Perfect Pi</string>
    <string name="about_calculating_pi_header">Calculation of pi</string>
    <string name="about_perfect_pi_description">Perfect Pi is a collaboration between Stockholm Mathematics Centre(SMC) and students from the computer science faculty at KTH in order to arise interest for mathematics in general and pi especially. The project is an Open source project licensed under Apache License Version 2.0 (http://www.apache.org/license). The source code is available on https://github.com/deltagruppen/circles/.</string>
    <string name="about_perfect_pi_header">About Perfect Pi</string>
    <string name="about_pi_header">Facts about pi</string>
    <string name="about_pi_title">Facts about pi</string>
    <string name="about_pi">Facts about pi</string>
    <string name="action_settings">Settings</string>
    <string name="actual_pi">Pi</string>
    <string name="app_info_title">About Perfect Pi</string>
    <string name="calculating_pi_title">Calculation of pi</string>
    <string name="closestStrokeColor">#40d81b60</string>
    <string name="about_app_contact_sl">director@math-stockholm.se</string>
    <string name="main_hand_arrow_description">hand_arrow</string>
    <string name="about_app_head_guiux">GUI/UX</string>
    <string name="main_head_instructions">Draw a circle</string>
    <string name="about_app_head_lead_programmer">Chief programmer</string>
    <string name="about_app_head_math_center">Stockholms Mathematics central</string>
    <string name="about_app_head_programmers">Programmers</string>
    <string name="about_app_head_project_leader">Project leader</string>
    <string name="about_app_head_secretary">Secretary</string>
    <string name="about_app_head_students">Students</string>
    <string name="about_app_head_user_testing">User testning</string>
    <string name="hello_world">Hello world!</string>
    <string name="highscore">High score</string>
    <string name="imperfectFillColor">#00000000</string>
    <string name="imperfectStrokeColor">#263238</string>
    <string name="instruction_part_one">Try to draw a circle as round as possible. An approximation of pi will be computed from the drawn circle.</string>
    <string name="language">Språk/Language</string>
    <string name="logo_text">A collaboration between Stockholm matemathic central and students at Royal technical institute(KTH).</string>
    <string name="main_circle_drawing_message1">Try again!</string>
    <string name="main_sidebar_attribution">A collaboration between Stockholm matemathics centre and students at KTH Royal Institute of Technology.</string>
    <string name="name_AE">Anna-Karin Evert</string>
    <string name="name_AKN">Aphia Kabata</string>
    <string name="name_AM">Alfrida Mattison</string>
    <string name="name_CA">Christoffer Alenskog</string>
    <string name="name_CEG">Chaimae El Ghouch</string>
    <string name="name_DJ">Dante Johansson</string>
    <string name="name_JYI">Jamila Yusuf Isse</string>
    <string name="name_MM">Macaully James Muir</string>
    <string name="name_PS">Patrik Schwermer</string>
    <string name="name_sl">Professor Svante Linusson</string>
    <string name="pi_calculation_intro">&#x3c0; is the ratio between a circles perimeter and it\'s diameter. In Perfect Pi the goal is to draw a circle with that same ratio. Begrudgingly this is impossible. To begin with &#x3c0; has an infinite amount of decimals so however close you get it\'s always possible to get even closer. There are also technical limitations. The display consists of pixels which form a grid. So all figures drawn are represented by patterns of horizontal and vertical lines which when zoomed out can be made to look like round shapes. But if you\'re really good and witty you can still get a value close to &#x3c0;.</string>
    <string name="pi_calculation_part1">The computations are based on the isoperimetric inequality. It says that for all circles the inequality 4&#x3c0;A ≤ L&#xb2; is true. This means that if you multiply a closed curve\'s area (A) with 4&#x3c0; the result will always be less or equal to the perimeter (L) squared.</string>
    <string name="pi_calculation_part2">By rewriting the isoperimetric inequality we end up with a relationship that can be used to compute the &#x3c0;-value for a circle (I).</string>
    <string name="pi_calculation_part3">When a user drags his finger on the display data is collected. This data is made up of points in an array. From every point a line is drawn to the subsequent point and when the user lifts his finger the computing starts.</string>
    <string name="pi_calculation_part4">Getting the length of the perimeter is easily done by adding the length of all the lines together. Calculating the area is a bit more tricky if you want a good result.</string>
    <string name="pi_calculation_part5">To calculate the area we use Green\'s theorem which expresses the area of a polygon as a line integral over it\'s perimeter, observe:</string>
    <string name="pi_calculation_part6">Finally the values are put into the isoperimetric inequality and out pops an incredibly accurate &#x3c0;-value for the drawn circle.</string>
    <string name="pi_calculation_title">Calculating pi</string>
    <string name="pi_fact_2">Pi is an irrational number, therefore it cannot be written as a fraction and it has an infinite decimal expansion. Two well-used approximations of pi are 3,14 and 22/7.</string>
    <string name="pi_fact_10">About 250 years b.c Archimedes calculated an approximation of pi by using an algorithm that consists of engraving a circle in between two polygons. By computing the circumference he found that the value of pi was between 223/71 and 22/7. Because of this pi is also called archimedes constant.</string>
    <string name="pi_fact_5">I = L/ (4*pi*d²)</string>
    <string name="pi_fact_4">Pi is used in astronomy and astrology to calculate paths and celestial bodies. Copernius and Galileo used pi to approximate the size of the earth and the distance to the moon. An example on how pi is used in astronomy is when calculating the apparent brightness (intensity) of a star using the following formula:</string>
    <string name="pi_fact_6">  Where I is the apparent brightness of the star in W/m²,  L is the luminosity of the star in  W,D is the distance to the star in meter.</string>
    <string name="pi_fact_1"> Pi is defined as the ratio of a circle\'s circumference to its diameter.</string>
    <string name="pi_fact_9">Albert Einstein was born on pi-day, March the 14th.</string>
    <string name="pi_fact_11">If you write "3.14" on piece of papper and hold it up to a mirror, it reflects the word "PIE".</string>
    <string name="pi_fact_8"> The identity e^(i*pi) + 1 = 0  is called Eulers identity and was discovered by Leonhard Euler in 1743. The identity is considered to be one the most beautiful equation in mathematics as it assembles the five most fundamentals numbers in mathematics: 0, 1, the unit of imaginary numbers ´i´, the base of natural logarithm ´e´ and ofcourse pi.</string>
    <string name="pi_fact_3"> "Pi-day" is celebrated on March the 14th which was chosen to resemble the approximation 3,14. Many people like to start the celebration around 1:59 pm which combined with the date ressembles 3.14159, which is an even better approximation of pi.</string>
    <string name="pi_fact_12">Around year 1644 Pietro Mengoli posed what is called the basel problem. the problem consisted of calculating the sum of infinite series:</string>
    <string name="pi_fact_13">∑(1/n^2)</string>
    <string name="pi_fact_14">This problem was solved by Leonhard Euler in 1743, who showed that ∑(1/n^2) → pi^2/6 as n → ∞.</string>
    <string name="pi_fact_7"> The worlds record for memorizing the value of pi was won by the Chinese Chao Lu, whom in 2005 memorized and recited the value up to the 67 890 first decimal places.</string>
    <string name="pi_fact_intro">The number pi has a thousand year old story. Ever since the babylonians around 2000 years b.c estimated the value of pi to 25/8, mathematicians and civilizations have struggled and attempted to get a more precise value and today we have estimations of pi with several billions decimal places. In order to illustrate what an amazing and fascinating number pi is, we have collected some fun facts that we have encountered during the development of the app.</string>
    <string name="pi_fact_title">10 facts about pi</string>
    <string name="pi">3,14159265</string>
    <string name="about_app_project_leader_details">Veronica Randleff \n randleff@kth.se</string>
    <string name="smc_logo_description">The SMC logo</string>
    <string name="teach_me_pi">Read more about pi</string>
    <string name="title_activity_about_calculating_pi">AboutCalculatingPi</string>
    <string name="title_activity_app_info">App Info</string>
    <string name="title_activity_calculating_pi">CalculatingPi</string>
    <string name="title_activity_pi_info">Pi Info</string>
    <string name="your_pi">Your pi</string>

</resources>